<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Sidney Liebrand's blog</title>
    <description>The official https://sidneyliebrand.io RSS feed</description>
    <link>https://sidneyliebrand.io</link>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 21:23:26 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <copyright>Copyright https://sidneyliebrand.io 2021</copyright>
    <category term="technology" />
    <item>
      <title>Sidney Liebrand's blog - How I became a web developer</title>
      <description>Even though I always knew I wanted to do something with computers, I was certain I could never become a web developer. This post will be my attempt at explaining how I got there anyway :)</description>
      <link>https://sidneyliebrand.io/blog/how-i-became-a-web-developer</link>
      <guid isPermalink="true">https://sidneyliebrand.io/blog/how-i-became-a-web-developer</guid>
      <pubdate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 14:06:00 GMT</pubdate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sidney Liebrand's blog - Converting .gif to web-safe video formats using ffmpeg</title>
      <description>This post shows how to convert .gif images to web-safe video formats using ffmpeg cli. These formats produce smaller files which means less data to load!</description>
      <link>https://sidneyliebrand.io/blog/converting-gif-to-web-safe-video-formats-using-ffmpeg</link>
      <guid isPermalink="true">https://sidneyliebrand.io/blog/converting-gif-to-web-safe-video-formats-using-ffmpeg</guid>
      <pubdate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 18:30:00 GMT</pubdate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sidney Liebrand's blog - Creating my own vim statusline</title>
      <description>Recently I decided to clean up my vim plugins once again, I do not think I use too many but I prefer to keep my setup simple. One of the things which bothered me was the configuration for lightline.vim in my vim config. It seemed needlessly complex and I wondered if I could recreate it without any plugins at all!</description>
      <link>https://sidneyliebrand.io/blog/creating-my-own-vim-statusline</link>
      <guid isPermalink="true">https://sidneyliebrand.io/blog/creating-my-own-vim-statusline</guid>
      <pubdate>Thu, 21 May 2020 00:12:34 GMT</pubdate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sidney Liebrand's blog - Fixing audio configuration after upgrading Ubuntu</title>
      <description>It is never fun when stuff breaks! This post is about me fixing some audio deficiencies after upgrading Ubuntu.</description>
      <link>https://sidneyliebrand.io/blog/fixing-audio-configuration-after-upgrading-ubuntu</link>
      <guid isPermalink="true">https://sidneyliebrand.io/blog/fixing-audio-configuration-after-upgrading-ubuntu</guid>
      <pubdate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:13:37 GMT</pubdate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sidney Liebrand's blog - And your metered paywall isn't part of my story, Medium</title>
      <description>I&apos;ve been greeted by the same &quot;Your story isn&apos;t part of the metered paywall&quot; message for a while now, and figured it was time to make a change in the right direction.</description>
      <link>https://sidneyliebrand.io/blog/and-your-metered-paywall-isnt-part-of-my-story-medium</link>
      <guid isPermalink="true">https://sidneyliebrand.io/blog/and-your-metered-paywall-isnt-part-of-my-story-medium</guid>
      <pubdate>Mon, 10 Jun 2019 04:36:22 GMT</pubdate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sidney Liebrand's blog - Recruiters who call during working hours</title>
      <description>Any kind of cold-call from some random recruiter or sales rep is annoying enough as is. Imagine my frustration when I got a call from a recruiter who called on the &lt;strong&gt;company phone&lt;/strong&gt; in the middle of a working day!</description>
      <link>https://sidneyliebrand.io/blog/recruiters-who-call-during-working-hours</link>
      <guid isPermalink="true">https://sidneyliebrand.io/blog/recruiters-who-call-during-working-hours</guid>
      <pubdate>Fri, 31 Aug 2018 22:41:19 GMT</pubdate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sidney Liebrand's blog - Codi.vim + fullscreen buffer</title>
      <description>Learn how to set up Codi.vim to create a fullscreen scratch buffer that also works with Vim splits. We will take a look at wrapping the &lt;code&gt;Codi&lt;/code&gt; command and improving the buffer name(s) as seen in &lt;code&gt;:ls&lt;/code&gt;.</description>
      <link>https://sidneyliebrand.io/blog/codi-vim-fullscreen-buffer</link>
      <guid isPermalink="true">https://sidneyliebrand.io/blog/codi-vim-fullscreen-buffer</guid>
      <pubdate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 07:55:24 GMT</pubdate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sidney Liebrand's blog - Vim tip: persistent undo</title>
      <description>Usually, when you open a file in your editor, make some changes, save and close, you lose the ability to &lt;kbd&gt;ctrl&lt;/kbd&gt;+&lt;kbd&gt;Z&lt;/kbd&gt;. Vim has a built in mechanism to persist changes made to files on disk. This may not sound that exciting, but what if your editor crashes while you have a set of changes you may want to revert stored?</description>
      <link>https://sidneyliebrand.io/blog/vim-tip-persistent-undo</link>
      <guid isPermalink="true">https://sidneyliebrand.io/blog/vim-tip-persistent-undo</guid>
      <pubdate>Sat, 04 Aug 2018 20:17:52 GMT</pubdate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sidney Liebrand's blog - How FZF and ripgrep improved my workflow</title>
      <description>In my never ending quest for simplicity I recently discovered FZF and ripgrep. Two command-line tools that have the potential to make every dag programming tasks easier. In this post I will explain how I use these tools to do things in a matter of keystrokes rather than having to re-google that command you keep forgetting &lt;strong&gt;every. single. time.&lt;/strong&gt;.</description>
      <link>https://sidneyliebrand.io/blog/how-fzf-and-ripgrep-improved-my-workflow</link>
      <guid isPermalink="true">https://sidneyliebrand.io/blog/how-fzf-and-ripgrep-improved-my-workflow</guid>
      <pubdate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 13:33:37 GMT</pubdate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sidney Liebrand's blog - The greatnesses and gotchas of YAML</title>
      <description>YAML is a great language for configuration files, it is a lot more flexible than JSON with comments and inheritance for example. While I was doing some research about YAML I found bits of information scattered all over the place so I attempted to piece the great things and the quirks together in a post!</description>
      <link>https://sidneyliebrand.io/blog/the-greatnesses-and-gotchas-of-yaml</link>
      <guid isPermalink="true">https://sidneyliebrand.io/blog/the-greatnesses-and-gotchas-of-yaml</guid>
      <pubdate>Sat, 23 Dec 2017 07:25:59 GMT</pubdate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sidney Liebrand's blog - A collection of Vim key binds</title>
      <description>In my never ending quest for an optimal Vim setup I am always looking for ways to improve. I&apos;ve used Vim for about two months now and I&apos;m still learning a lot. In this post I&apos;m going to take you through a part of my .vimrc that describes my non-plugin key binds.</description>
      <link>https://sidneyliebrand.io/blog/a-collection-of-vim-key-binds</link>
      <guid isPermalink="true">https://sidneyliebrand.io/blog/a-collection-of-vim-key-binds</guid>
      <pubdate>Sat, 16 Sep 2017 13:11:03 GMT</pubdate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sidney Liebrand's blog - Combining Caniuse with FZF</title>
      <description>There is caniuse.com which you can use to search online, but what if you&apos;re a lazy dev like me that likes to keep his stuff in the terminal? Well, for this reason I wrote a small wrapper using some of my all time favorite tools: Ruby and FZF!</description>
      <link>https://sidneyliebrand.io/blog/combining-caniuse-with-fzf</link>
      <guid isPermalink="true">https://sidneyliebrand.io/blog/combining-caniuse-with-fzf</guid>
      <pubdate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 11:47:27 GMT</pubdate>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sidney Liebrand's blog - Switching to ASDF version manager</title>
      <description>Depending on how many languages you program in, getting all their version managers installed, added to &lt;code&gt;$PATH&lt;/code&gt;, configured etc... becomes quite a pain when setting up a new system, or even figuring out how this one works because you&apos;ve used something else for a while.</description>
      <link>https://sidneyliebrand.io/blog/switching-to-asdf-version-manager</link>
      <guid isPermalink="true">https://sidneyliebrand.io/blog/switching-to-asdf-version-manager</guid>
      <pubdate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 21:04:44 GMT</pubdate>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>